myvodafone.com.au 2017-06-29

# Our Privacy Policy To Protect You | Vodafone Australia

Protecting your privacy is a big deal. At Vodafone we’re strict about how we handle personal information. This privacy policy outlines how we collect, store, use and disclose personal information. It also confirms our obligations under the Privacy Act 1988 and the Telecommunications Act 1997. 

### What is your personal information?

In this privacy policy, the term ‘personal information’ has the meaning given to it in the Privacy Act. Personal information is information we collect which identifies you, or can be used to identify you.

### Why do we collect personal information?

We need to collect some personal details from you to provide you with our services and products. Without collecting your identifying information when you join us, we’re not allowed by law to provide you with the products and services you want. After you join, we may also need to collect additional personal information so we can manage your account and provide our services and products.

### What personal information do we collect?

The information we collect about you depends on the products and services you use. It may include the below:

  * Your name, date of birth and contact details. Contact details may include your home address, email address and phone number.
  * Your bank account and credit card details.
  * Information to prove your identity. This could be your driver’s licence or another approved ID.
  * Information relating to your credit worthiness.
  * Your employment history, if you apply for a job with us.
  * Details of products and services we’ve supplied you or you’ve asked about.
  * Details needed to deliver those products and services or answer your questions.
  * When you tell us, products, services or lifestyle activities you like. Also, how you like to use our products and services.
  * Websites you visit and online searches you do.
  * Details about your account. This includes your password and username.
  * Your use of mobile voice and data services.
  * Information about you that you provide us directly or indirectly when online.
  * Information you provide to us through surveys.

Some of the information above may be sensitive information. For example, it could be about your health, race, ethnic origin or religious beliefs. You consent to us collecting that information as outlined above, including when you provide it to us directly, or when you leave a message for one of our customers who uses our paging and message service.

### Information about how you use our products and services

We may collect the below:

  * Phone numbers that you call or send messages to.
  * Phone numbers that you receive calls and messages from.
  * The date, time and length of the calls and messages you send or receive with us. Also, your general location at the time of these calls and messages.
  * The level of service you receive. This may include details of network faults or events which may affect our services.
  * The date, time and length of your internet browsing. Also, your general location at the time.

### How do we collect personal information?

We collect your personal information if you do any of the below:

  * Provide information to us in account application forms, service enquiry forms.
  * Provide information to us when you buy products or services from our website.
  * Subscribe to newsletters, alerts or other services from us.
  * Take part in a competition, prize draw or survey.
  * Visit our website, online store, Facebook page and other pages that we own and manage.
  * Visit external websites and perform online searches using your device.
  * Visit external pages through our portals like MyVodafone.
  * Make calls to Vodafone. These calls may be recorded for training, quality and business purposes.
  * Use your mobile device.
  * Use your mobile device and this results in contact between your device and our network. This contact might tell us about you, your device, your use of our services and your general location.
  * Apply for a position to work at Vodafone.

### Information collected from other sources

We may collect personal information from the below:

  * Other companies in the Vodafone group.
  * Credit reporting agencies, law enforcement agencies and other government entities.
  * Entities that provide services to us. This includes entities to which we may disclose your personal information. We explain who these entities are below.
  * Publicly available sources of information, like market research providers.

We may also collect information in different ways. We will take all reasonable steps to let you know if we do.

### Paging and message service

We offer a paging and message service to our customers. If you call one of those customers and you would like to leave a message, we will collect from you details like your name, telephone number and any details in your message. We will then send your message and those details to our customer as part of the service. We will not use or disclose your details in other ways. We will hold and manage your details as set out in this policy.

### How do we use cookies?

We might also use cookies and other techniques such as web beacons. Cookies are small text files stored in your browser. Web beacons are small, clear picture files used to see how you use our website. This helps us understand how we can make our online products more relevant to you.

We may use a persistent cookie, which is a cookie that stays linked to your browser. A persistent cookie is used to record your visits so we can recognise you if you visit our website again. It also lets us keep track of products or services you view so that, with your consent, we can send you news about them.

We also use cookies to measure traffic patterns, to see which areas of our website have been visited and to measure total transaction patterns. This helps us see how our site is used so that we can improve our online products and services. You can set your browser so your computer stops cookies or lets you know each time a website tries to set a cookie.

We may also log your IP address. Your IP address is your computer’s electronic Internet address. We may collect your IP address to see trends, run the website, track user movements, and gather broad demographic information.

### How do we use your personal information?

We may use your personal information and usage information in the ways set out below:

  * Providing you with phone and data products and services. This might include extra services not in your agreement with us. These services may tell us about where you are when using your mobile device.
  * Contacting you with messages about changes to our products or services.
  * Generating bills, managing your account, and carrying out debt-recovery.
  * Processing orders or applications to become a customer.
  * Verifying your identity.
  * Carrying out credit checks and credit reporting.
  * Dealing with questions, complaints and other customer care activities.
  * Carrying out market analysis and research.
  * Development of our products and services.
  * Understanding how customers use our network, products and services anonymously and personally.
  * Analysing the things that interest you as well as where you use your mobile device. We use those details to provide you with services, products and information suited to your needs, interests and location.
  * Contacting you about our products and services and those offered under other brands that our group owns. This may include marketing these products to you. See below for more information about direct marketing communications.
  * Identifying your location so we can send you emergency alerts.
  * Protecting our network and managing the volume of calls, TXTs and other use of our network. For example, we identify peak periods of use so our network can better handle the volume at those times.
  * Conducting internal investigations in relation to crime and fraud prevention, detection, recovery or prosecution.
  * Training our staff.

For other purposes, Vodafone will ask for your consent to use your personal information.

### Direct marketing communications

We may send you direct marketing messages and information about the below:

  * Our products, services, discounts, competitions and special promotions that may be of interest to you.
  * Offers or promotions based on how you use our products and services for example your data, calling and messaging activities, location information and browsing information.
  * Other companies' products and services (including offers and discounts we’ve arranged for our customers) we think may interest you, if you’ve chosen to receive this information.

This marketing material may be sent by various methods. This includes but is not limited to, telephone, post, fax and any form of electronic message (including, but not limited to, email, SMS, MMS, PXT or Video PXT).

You consent to us sending you marketing material by any of those methods. If you indicate a preferred method of communication, we will try to use that method when practical.

Also, at any time you may opt-out of receiving marketing material from us by contacting us. Or you can use any opt-out method provided in the material. We’ll make sure your name is taken off our mailing list.

We may give your personal information to other organisations for the purposes of direct marketing. These organisations are limited to our dealers and sales agents working directly on behalf of Vodafone. Otherwise, you can separately opt-in to receiving third-party marketing through a specific promotion.

### How can you opt-out of marketing materials?

If you’d rather not get our direct marketing material, it’s easy to opt-out. Check out our [ support article](https://www.vodafone.com.au/support/contact/marketing-messages) to find out how.

Or, you may contact [ 1555](tel:1555) from your Vodafone mobile or call [ 1300 650 410](tel:1300650410) from any phone. You can also use any opt-out methods provided in our marketing material, and we'll do the rest.

Just a heads up that we’ll still need to send you essential information about your account, your service or plan and other information required by law.

### Who can we provide your personal information to?

Vodafone might disclose your personal information both within and outside Australia to the entities below:

  * Credit providers or credit reporting agencies for the purposes permitted under the Privacy Act and credit reporting legislation.
  * Our service and content providers including the providers of IT services and mailing services.
  * Our dealers, agents, contractors and advisers.
  * Our mobile device manufacturers and repairers.
  * Our providers of marketing, research, call centre and telemarketing services.
  * Vodafone Hutchison Australia and other companies in the Vodafone group.
  * Your authorised representatives or legal advisors.
  * Our professional advisors including lawyers, accountants, tax advisors and auditors.
  * Debt collection agencies and other parties that assist with debt-recovery functions.
  * Law enforcement bodies to assist in their functions, courts of law or as otherwise required or authorised by law.
  * Emergency services (if you make an emergency call) or other service providers assisting in emergency situations.
  * Regulatory or government bodies to resolve customer complaints or disputes both internally and externally. Or to comply with any investigation by one of those bodies.
  * Other telco companies for the purposes of dealing with unwelcome calls and mobile number portability issues.

We are required by law to disclose personal information about you to the operator of the Integrated Public Number Database (IPND). Information we may be required to disclose includes, your name, physical address, telephone number and email address. Personal information in the IPND is used to assist emergency services and safeguard national security. If you consent, information from the IPND may also be published in public directories or used by directory assistance. IPND information may also be used for research with approval by the ACMA.

### Do we disclose your personal information outside Australia?

Vodafone may disclose personal information to other companies in the Vodafone group as well as third party suppliers and service providers located overseas for some of the purposes listed above.

We take reasonable steps to make sure the overseas recipients of your personal information do not breach the privacy obligations relating to it.

We may store or sometimes disclose personal information to entities outside Australia. Some of these entities are:

  * Companies in the Vodafone group located in the UK and Hong Kong.
  * Vodafone’s data hosting and other service providers located in India, Japan, New Zealand, the Philippines, Fiji, Singapore, Sweden, the UK and the USA.

### How do we hold and protect your personal information?

The security of your personal information is important to us. We take all reasonable steps to securely store your personal information so it’s protected from unauthorised use, access, modification or disclosure. This includes both physical and electronic security measures.

We sometimes use service providers to process, manage and store personal information. Where we do, we require those service providers to comply with strict requirements about the use and protection of your details.

We also ensure that your personal information are seen and used only by staff who need it to do their jobs. Our staff securely destroy any printed documents containing your details.

We run checks of our systems, service providers and staff to make sure that your personal information is held and used properly. We give our staff special training about privacy and the proper use of your details.

### How can you protect your account from unauthorised access?

Anyone who knows your account PIN or online username and password can access your account. You must keep this information secure. Only share these details with people you authorise to access and manage your Vodafone account. Vodafone accepts no responsibility for information it discloses to parties who know your PIN, username or password.

### How accurate is the personal information we hold about you?

We take all reasonable measures to make sure the personal information we hold is accurate, complete and up to date. However, the accuracy of your information is largely dependent on what you provide us. To make sure we’ve got your most current and accurate details, please let us know when your information changes. For example, if you change your name or move house.

### Can you access and correct the personal information we hold about you?

Yes, but there may be times where we cannot grant you access to the personal information we hold. For example, we may not grant access to information if it could interfere with the privacy of others or if it would result in a breach of confidentiality. If that happens, we will give you written reasons for any refusal.

To request your personal information complete this form , and return it to the address provided. We won’t charge you for simply making the request or for making any corrections to your personal information. We may charge reasonable costs for carrying out your request.

If you think your personal information is out of date, or may not be accurate or complete you can ask for it to be updated. If we do not agree that there are grounds to change it, we’ll add a note to the personal information stating that you disagree.

### How can you report a breach of your privacy?

If you believe your privacy has been compromised, please fill in this Privacy Breach form and return it to the address provided. A member of our Privacy team will get in touch within 10 business days.

If you believe that we have not dealt with your concerns you may lodge a complaint with the Australian Privacy Commissioner or the Telecommunications Industry Ombudsman.

Australian Privacy Commissioner: GPO Box 5218 Sydney NSW 2001. Telephone: 1300 363 992. Email:[enquiries@oaic.gov.au](mailto:enquiries@oaic.gov.au) (preferred)

Telecommunications Industry Ombudsman: PO Box 276, Collins Street West, VIC 8007. Telephone: 1800 062 058. Website: [ https://www.tio.com.au/making-a-complaint](https://www.tio.com.au/making-a-complaint)

### Contact us

If you have any questions about your privacy, or if you would like a printed copy of this privacy policy (free of charge), [ please contact us](http://www.vodafone.com.au/contact).

Call [ 1555](tel:1555) from your Vodafone mobile.

Call [ 1300 650 410](tel:1300650410) from any phone.

Fax us on 1300 308 869.

Our postal address is:  
Vodafone Customer Care PO Box 2580   
Kingston Delivery Centre   
Kingston, Tasmania 7050

### **Vodafone Privacy Policy, April 2015**

Vodafone Hutchison Australia Pty Limited ABN 76 096 304 620.

Vodafone Australia Limited ABN 86 056 161 043.

Vodafone Pty Limited ABN 76 062 954 554.

Vodafone Network Pty Limited ABN 31 081 918 461.

Registered address: Level 7, 40 Mount Street, North Sydney NSW 2060. References to ‘Vodafone Group’ may include Vodafone Hutchison Australia and its parent and related companies.
